Shamalan Rajesvaran

<u>shamalanraj@gmail.com</u> | (+60) 17 252 3699 | <u>linkedin.com/in/shamalan/</u> Subang Jaya, Selangor

Final Year Data Analytics Student

A versatile, results-oriented student with multiple comprehensive experiences taking up leadership roles in prominent student organisations and NGOs. Proven problem solving and analytical thinking skills, a fast-learning curve and ability to adapt to evolving industry trends. Possesses a strong passion in the field of data analytics and propensity to grow among like-minded people. A dedicated individual with the drive and skillset to significantly enhance a company's value.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Information Systems (Honours) (Data Analytics): Sunway University

March 2020 - Present

Current CGPA: 3.81

Awards: Jeffrey Cheah ACE Scholarship

Diploma in Information Technology: Sunway College March 2020

CGPA: 3.84

Awards: Jeffrey Cheah Entrance Scholarship

Sijil Peperiksaan Malaysia: Methodist Boys' School Kuala Lumpur 2017

Grades: 9A

IGCSE First Language English 2017

Grade: A

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Industrial Trainee Dec 2019 – Feb 2020

LE Global Services Sdn Bhd (LGMS Penetration Testing Expert)

- Learned and assisted in performing and analyzing the results of the Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing (VAPT).
- Collaborated and liaised with the interns and team leaders to complete any ad hoc research and tasks.
- Successfully conducted the Penetration Test at the client's site while producing a comprehensive report.

EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCE

Project Director Industry Insights 2021

Jan 2021 - Present

International Council of Malaysian Scholars and Associates (ICMS)

- Spearheaded and coordinated an international network of 26 Malaysian associates to execute ICMS' Flagship event with a budget of RM18,000.
- Liaised closely with both the Council's leadership team and current Partners & Sponsors from all 5 participating firms (Sunway, Maybank, Axiata, Deloitte and UNIQLO).
- Increased year-on-year number of applications by 48.2% through effective marketing and enhancement of the content of the event.
- Successfully led negotiations for sponsorship deals with Deloitte and UNIQLO to provide in-kind sponsorship for the specific workshop with a valuation exceeding RM 7000.

President, Sunway College Student Council

Jan 2019 – June 2019

Sunway College

- Led a team of 35 council members to organise a panel session with notable political figures such as YB Michelle Ng, YB Lim Yi Wei and YB Jamaliah Jamaluddin to spur political awareness amongst the youth.
- Actively participated in Sunway College's management meetings such as Sunway Sustainable Campus Committee (SSCC) and Food and Beverage (F&B) meetings to raise Student Affairs related issues.
- Collectively raised a total of RM 700 from a Community Service Initiative which was donated to SHELTER Home for Children in support of children who have suffered abuse and neglect.

Sunway University Toastmasters Club, Innovative Planning 4

June 2018 - Present

Sunway University

- Actively delivered a total of 20 speeches and 20 speech evaluations as per the Toastmasters manual.
- Successfully completed 4 levels of Toastmasters International's Innovative Planning Pathway.

Action Learning Programme, Emerging Leaders Asia

Axiata's Young Talent Development Programme (AYTP)

- Consulted the CEO of Espressolab Asia to produce innovative business strategies and carried out a step-by-step approach to dissect Espressolab's pain points and ultimately recommend solutions.
- Delivered a go-to-market strategy with validated quantitative data, in addition to thorough qualitative analysis.
- Successfully increased Espressolab Asia's Instagram following by 20% through a carefully structured and planned marketing strategy.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Vice-Chairperson, National Youth Committee

Oct 2020 – Present

Amnesty International Malaysia (AIM)

- Worked actively in developing and establishing the Amnesty Youth Network comprising of 55 youth activists nationwide through youth leadership and innovative thinking to the movement.
- Organised monthly Youth Network meetings to engage with the Youth Members of AIM.
- Founded Amnesty International Malaysia's 3rd Youth Club in Malaysia at Sunway University alongside a team of 4 members.

Community & U - Leadership and Volunteerism, Champion

July 2018 – Dec 2018

Soroptimist International Club of Bangsar

- Supported and established a learning space fully equipped with books and learning materials at MANNA Learning Centre, Sunway to assist the Myanmar Refugee below the age of 7 through multiple activities.
- Actively engaged in a three-month project to paint murals, build shelves, collect donated books and purchase learning materials to furnish the learning space at the centre.
- Conducted intensive sessions to teach the Myanmar Refugee children basic conversations in English.
- Supported the single Myanmar Refugee mothers by teaching them how to make hand-made recycle bags and providing them with the profits from the sale.

Rover, 10th KL Air Scouts Group

Jan 2013 - Present

Methodist Boys' School Kuala Lumpur

- Demonstrated leadership skills as the Organising Team of the 10th KL Campfire 2017 and emceed throughout the event
- Contributed to society by taking part in frequent community service activities to assist the underprivileged, marginalised and needy.
- Achieved the highest award upon completion of 10 crucial activities at the Kuala Lumpur International Scouts Jamboree 2016 attended by 3000 scouts from 15 different countries.

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

ICAEW's Malaysia Case Challenge, National Champion

March 2021 - Jun 2021

- Emerged as eventual champions in the Malaysian Case Challenge amongst 20 teams.
- Represented team Malaysia in the ICAEW Greater China and Southeast Asia Regional Case Challenge to compete amongst teams from China, Indonesia, Singapore and Vietnam.
- Formulated solutions and strategies for the survival of hotels through smart revenue streams during the Covid-19 pandemic through a well thought and data-backed analysis.

CEO Challenge, 2nd Runners Up

July 2020

Axiata's University Leadership Development Programme (ULDP)

- Shortlisted as one of the 52 students from a pool of 4000 Malaysian students worldwide.
- ULDP is a 2-week leadership programme that focuses on developing soft skills and business acumen. It involved Business Challenges, Stakeholder Management as well as Sales and Marketing. Helmed roles such as Chief Executive Officer (CEO) and Chief Technology Officer (CTO).
- Ultimately emerged as the 2nd Runner Up for the CEO Challenge amongst 7 other teams.

Basic Occupational First Aid, CPR, AED Training

Jan 2018 - Present

Cert Academy

• Successfully completed the training to obtain the BOFA-C certification.

OTHERS

Technical Skills: Python, Java, HTML, SQL, PHP, SAS, R Studio, Hadoop, Linux Commands **Languages:** Fluent in English and Malay, Elementary proficiency in Mandarin and Tamil